{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Information Assurance & Security (Cybersecurity Fundamentals)",
    "Term": "Prelims",
    "Title": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities || 01 Handout 1",
    "LastModified": "18 February 2025",
    "Authors": [
      "Alexander Oro"
    ],
    "References": [
      "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities || 01 Handout 1"
    ]
  },
  "quizData":  [
    {
      "question": "In the anatomy of a cyberattack, what is the first step?",
      "answer": "Reconnaissance",
      "choices": [
        "Attack",
        "Expansion",
        "Obfuscation",
        "Reconnaissance"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the anatomy of a cyberattack, what is the second step?",
      "answer": "Attack",
      "choices": [
        "Attack",
        "Expansion",
        "Obfuscation",
        "Reconnaissance"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the anatomy of a cyberattack, what is the third step?",
      "answer": "Expansion",
      "choices": [
        "Attack",
        "Expansion",
        "Obfuscation",
        "Reconnaissance"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the anatomy of a cyberattack, what is the final step?",
      "answer": "Obfuscation",
      "choices": [
        "Attack",
        "Expansion",
        "Obfuscation",
        "Reconnaissance"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What stage of a cyberattack involves researching and gathering information about the target?",
      "answer": "Reconnaissance",
      "choices": [
        "Attack",
        "Expansion",
        "Obfuscation",
        "Reconnaissance"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What stage of a cyberattack involves infiltrating the organization's network?",
      "answer": "Attack",
      "choices": [
        "Attack",
        "Expansion",
        "Obfuscation",
        "Reconnaissance"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What stage of a cyberattack involves intruding all systems on the network using malicious programs?",
      "answer": "Expansion",
      "choices": [
        "Attack",
        "Expansion",
        "Obfuscation",
        "Reconnaissance"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What stage of a cyberattack involves hackers hiding their tracks to mask the origins of the attack?",
      "answer": "Obfuscation",
      "choices": [
        "Attack",
        "Expansion",
        "Obfuscation",
        "Reconnaissance"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many cybersecurity risks are listed that may impact organizations?",
      "answer": "Seven",
      "choices": [
        "Four",
        "Five",
        "Six",
        "Seven"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What has revolutionized the way organizations conduct business today, but also brought vulnerabilities due to its widespread use?",
      "answer": "Technology",
      "choices": [
        "Globalization",
        "Artificial Intelligence",
        "Automation",
        "Technology"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "From publishing to automotive, industries are facing new, evolving services and business models due to what?",
      "answer": "Technology",
      "choices": [
        "Globalization",
        "Regulation",
        "Competition",
        "Technology"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What two prevailing trends will heighten cyber risks dramatically?",
      "answer": "Supply Chain",
      "choices": [
        "Economic",
        "Globalization",
        "Technological",
        "Supply Chain"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Companies’ growing reliance on third-party and even fourth-party vendors and service providers presents attackers with new openings into what?",
      "answer": "Supply Chain",
      "choices": [
        "Business Operations",
        "Employee Networks",
        "Internet of Things",
        "Supply Chain"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of devices are everywhere, with each one in a workplace now presenting a potential security risk?",
      "answer": "Internet of Things",
      "choices": [
        "Mobile",
        "Networked",
        "Wireless",
        "Internet of Things"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Many companies don’t securely manage or even inventory all devices of what type, already resulting in breaches?",
      "answer": "Internet of Things",
      "choices": [
        "BYOD",
        "Legacy",
        "Networked",
        "Internet of Things"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Connectivity to the Internet improves what dramatically, but increased connectivity also leads to new security vulnerabilities?",
      "answer": "Business Operations",
      "choices": [
        "Employee Morale",
        "Supply Chains",
        "Regulatory Compliance",
        "Business Operations"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "How does increased connectivity impact the attack surface, making it easier for attackers to move laterally across an entire network?",
      "answer": "Business Operations",
      "choices": [
        "Employee Productivity",
        "Supply Chain Efficiency",
        "Regulatory Compliance",
        "Business Operations"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who remains one of the most common causes of breaches, yet often doesn't realize the true threat they pose to an entire organization’s cybersecurity?",
      "answer": "Employees",
      "choices": [
        "Hackers",
        "Malicious Insiders",
        "Longanisa Seller",
        "Employees"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "As technology continues to impact every job function, what must organizations establish to mitigate insider risks?",
      "answer": "Employees",
      "choices": [
        "Hackers",
        "Longanisa Seller",
        "Board of Directors",
        "Employees"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is designed to protect and insulate businesses and their customers, but cannot be the sole focus in cybersecurity?",
      "answer": "Regulatory",
      "choices": [
        "Employees",
        "Board of Directors",
        "Business Operations",
        "Regulatory"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Firms must balance both new regulations and evolving cyber threats, which will require vigilance regarding what?",
      "answer": "Regulatory",
      "choices": [
        "Employees",
        "Board of Directors",
        "Business Operations",
        "Regulatory"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Whose oversight continues to be a point of emphasis, with recent history showing an expanding personal risk for directors and officers?",
      "answer": "Board of Directors",
      "choices": [
        "Technological",
        "Financial",
        "Operational",
        "Board of Directors"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who must expand their focus in cybersecurity and set a strong tone across the company, not only for actions taken after a cyber-incident but also for proactive preparation and planning?",
      "answer": "Board of Directors",
      "choices": [
        "Employees",
        "Management",
        "Faculty",
        "Board of Directors"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which type of malware specifically aims to extort money by blocking access to files or computer systems?",
      "answer": "Ransomware",
      "choices": [
        "Spyware",
        "Adware",
        "Scareware",
        "Ransomware"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Even after paying the ransom, what type of attack may still result in unrecovered files or systems?",
      "answer": "Ransomware",
      "choices": [
        "Spyware",
        "Adware",
        "Scareware",
        "Ransomware"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What general term refers to any software designed to gain unauthorized access or cause damage to a computer?",
      "answer": "Malware",
      "choices": [
        "Firewall",
        "Antivirus",
        "Anti-malware",
        "Malware"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What deceptive tactic tricks users into revealing sensitive information or making payments?",
      "answer": "Social Engineering",
      "choices": [
        "Encryption",
        "Data Loss Prevention",
        "Vulnerability Scanning",
        "Social Engineering"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of attack often involves clicking on links, downloading malware, or trusting a malicious source due to deception?",
      "answer": "Social Engineering",
      "choices": [
        "Encryption",
        "Data Loss Prevention",
        "Vulnerability Scanning",
        "Social Engineering"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What specific form of attack uses fraudulent emails that mimic reputable sources to steal sensitive data?",
      "answer": "Phishing",
      "choices": [
        "Spamming",
        "Spoofing",
        "Pharming",
        "Phishing"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the most prevalent type of cyberattack, often used to steal credit card numbers and login information?",
      "answer": "Phishing",
      "choices": [
        "Spamming",
        "Spoofing",
        "Pharming",
        "Phishing"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are used for encrypting malware to obscure and make the data difficult to detect?",
      "answer": "Crypting Services",
      "choices": [
        "Antivirus Software",
        "Firewalls",
        "Intrusion Detection Systems",
        "Crypting Services"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What term defines as buying and selling of malware on the “Dark Web,” a black market for cyber criminals?",
      "answer": "Crimeware",
      "choices": [
        "The Surface Web",
        "The Deep Web",
        "Cloud Storage Platforms",
        "Crimeware"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of software is specifically designed to enable individuals with limited technical skills to commit cybercrimes?",
      "answer": "Crimeware",
      "choices": [
        "Ransomware",
        "Spyware",
        "Adware",
        "Crimeware"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of malware allows hackers to remotely control an infected computer, steal data, or use its camera?",
      "answer": "Remote Administration Tools",
      "choices": [
        "Rootkits",
        "Trojan Horses",
        "Worms",
        "Remote Administration Tools"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What specific type of malware tracks keystrokes to capture confidential conversations and login credentials?",
      "answer": "Keyloggers",
      "choices": [
        "Spyware",
        "Adware",
        "Trojan Horses",
        "Keyloggers"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What works by targeting users who think they are visiting a trusted site but then get redirected to a malicious site?",
      "answer": "Exploit Kits",
      "choices": [
        "Phishing Emails",
        "Malicious Websites",
        "Drive-by Downloads",
        "Exploit Kits"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What term refers to stolen data like credit card numbers and login credentials that are often sold on the Dark Web?",
      "answer": "Leaked Data",
      "choices": [
        "Encrypted Data",
        "Anonymized Data",
        "Protected Health Information",
        "Leaked Data"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What devices are physically implanted in POS terminals, ATMs, or gas pumps to steal card data?",
      "answer": "Card Skimmers",
      "choices": [
        "Keyloggers",
        "Spyware",
        "Trojan Horses",
        "Card Skimmers"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What poses a significant security risk due to lack of security patches, often caused by outdated systems?",
      "answer": "Unpatched Systems",
      "choices": [
        "Updated Systems",
        "Legacy Systems",
        "Networked Systems",
        "Unpatched Systems"
      ],
      "reference": "Introduction to Risks, Threats, and Vulnerabilities",
      "term": "Prelims"
    }
  ]
}